Catherwood, Martin P. Papers /3025
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Martin P. Catherwood Papers
1943-1997
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Catherwood, Martin P.
/3025
12.22 cubic feet
11.2 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Papers of Martin P. Catherwood, including correspondence and speeches, mostly from either before or after his time as the Dean of the ILR School. Papers from his time as Dean mostly concern NYC Transit.
3073839
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 12, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, January 14, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3025 MB: Martin P. Catherwood Memorabilia /4041: Catherwood, Martin P. Papers. Additional. /4052: Catherwood, Martin P. Papers. Additional. /4198 MB: Catherwood, Martin P. Academic Robe, Hood and Cap. Additional Memorabilia. /4292m: Catherwood, Martin P. Framed Letter to Joseph Raffel
Catherwood, M. P. (Martin Paul), 1904-1978.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.
3073839
- International Association for Governmental Labor Officials (Box 1)
  - IAGLO Executive Board Meeting Washington, D.C., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Speeches IAGLO -- President's Report July 25, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Speeches IAGLO President's Report, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - IAGLO Executive Board Meeting Washington, D.C., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Commissioner IAGLO -- Kirschner Report, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - IAGLO - IAGLO Constitution, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - IAGLO Executive Board Minutes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Commissioner IAGLO -- Executive Board Meeting San Francisco, Calif. 12/66, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IAGLO Executive Board Meeting Washington, D.C., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Industrial Commissioner IAGLO - Executive Board Meeting, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Industrial Commissioner IAGLO Executive Board Meeting, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Industrial Commissioner IAGLO - Ad Hoc Committee on Safety and Health Legislation, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Industrial Commissioner, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Industrial Commissioner IAGLO - Ad Hoc Committee on Walsh-Healey Agreements, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Speeches (Box 2)
  - Speeches, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Speeches, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Speeches, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Speeches, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Speeches, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Speeches H.F.R. Catherwood Lecture, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Speeches Cornell ILR Manpower Conference, N.Y.C., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Speeches 25th Anniversary NYS Women's Council Cornell University, Ithaca, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - NYS Women's Council Statler Club, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Industrial Commissioner (Box 3)
  - Industrial Commissioner, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Industrial Commissioner National Academy of Arbitrators, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Industrial Commissioner Governor's Club, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Commissioner Parties, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Industrial Commissioner MPC -- Quote File, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Industrial Commissioner Federal Legislation, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Industrial Commissioner Jan. 1970- Cornell Board of Trustees (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Commissioner Cornell - Admission, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Industrial Commissioner - Cornell - School on Industrial and Labor Relations, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Industrial Commissioner - Cornell University Council, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Industrial Commissioner - Cornell Board of Trustees, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Industrial Commissioner - Cornell (Oral History Program), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Industrial Commissioner Bibliography, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Industrial Commissioner Canadian Assoc. of Administrators of Labour Legislation, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Photographs, Scrapbooks (Box 4)
  - Jack Silverman's International Cabaret Restaurant, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Bound, Photographs
  - Catherwood Photographs, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ralph J. Vatalaro (Box 4, Folder 3)
    2 Photographs
  - Catherwood Photographs (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Bound, 40+ Photographs
  - Industrial Commissioner Photographs, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    7+ Photographs
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Catherwood Photographs (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Bound, 50+ Photographs
  - Catherwood Photographs, 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Bound, 20+ Photographs
- NYS Div. of State Planning. Files; Public information scrapbooks; Pictures; Framed citations (Box 5)
  - N.Y.S. Planning Council 14th Annual Meeting + Minutes, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - State Planning Council -- Correspondence, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Black, Russell VanNest, (N.J.), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Callison -- Planning, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Planning - Bonner, J. Franklin, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Planning Clarke, Gilmore D., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cullings, E.S., 1939 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Planning Chas. W. Eliot, 2nd, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - N.Y.S. Planning Council, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Drainage Basin, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Land Use (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Memo. On Water Resources (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Planning - Reports sent for, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Catherwood (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Budget - Annual Report (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Planning - Miscellaneous Letters, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Expense Account Division of State Planning, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- NYS Div. of State Planning. Files; Public information scrapbooks; Pictures; Framed citations (Box 6)
  - Planning Commisr. Mark Graves, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Planning - Heydecker, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Planning Hollister, S.C., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Planning Hollister, S.C., 1938 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Governor Lehman, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Planning Lewis, Harold M., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Planning Milton E. Loomis, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Planning - MacKesey, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - McKernon, Edward, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Planning Harold Merrill, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Neufield, Dr. Maurice F., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Raper, Dean Chas. L., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Planning - Straus, Dorothy, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Planning Wallerstein, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Planning Colonel Waring, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Moffat, Abbot Low, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Letter to and From the, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Minutes of Planning Conferences, 1935-1938 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Planning Board - Mimeographed Bulletins, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - State Planning Council - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Incodel, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Incodel, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Incodel - 1940 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Neufield talk - Population Trends in New Jersey, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Planning, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Planning, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Planning - Monthly Letters, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Letters from Council Members, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Planning - Letters - May, 1938-1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - National Resources Board (Harold Merrill), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Annual Report state Planning, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - State Planning = Misc., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Plaques, etc. (Box 7)
- Plaques, etc. (Box 8)
- Corresp. (1940), Planning Comm. Minutes (Box 9)
  - Exhibit No. 159, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Bound
  - Neufield, Dr. Maurice Jan. - June 1940 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Neufield, Dr. Maurice, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - N.Y.S. Education Dept., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Pond, Dr. Chester B., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Raper, Dean Charles L., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Spelman Fund, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Straus, Miss Dorothy, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Turner, Hon. Ellwood J., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Wallerstein, Morton L., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Waring, Colonel J. M. S., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - State Planning Letters L-Z, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Form Letters, etc., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Craig, J. G., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Crockett, A. E., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Daily, Mark A., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Eliot, Charles W., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Frederick, Joseph C., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Ives, Irving M., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Lehman, Hon. Herbert H., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Wallerstein, Morton L., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - State Planning Letters, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - State Planning, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Memoranda, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Joint Legis. Com. On Interstate Coop. Subcommittees, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Labor and Industrial Coordinating Committee (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Division of Commerce, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Expense Accounts State Planning, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Expense Accounts State Planning, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Applications, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - State Planning Letters A-K, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - State Planning Letters L-Z, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Black, Russell VanNest, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Blaisdell, Thomas, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Bonner, J. Franklin, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Consultant's Report, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Botsford, Samuel B., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Brown, Hon. Richard P., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Browning, Homer, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Callison, Eugene H., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Clarke, Dean Gilmore D., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Cullings, Edwin S., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Daly, Mark A., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Eliot, Charles W., 1939 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Frederick, Joseph C., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Graves, Com. Mark, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Harvey, Mrs. Salem, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Hollister, Dean S.C., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Hyde, John W., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Lehman, Hon. Herbert H., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Ives, Irving W., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Lewis, Harold M., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - May, Stacy, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - McKernon, Edward, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Merrill Harold, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 56)
- Arbitration cases, emergency boards. 106-110 (Box 10)
  - Board of Arbitration -- No. 225, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration Hearing -- Syracuse, New York, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Arbitrator's Report -- Arbitration File No. 58A/2170, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Arbitration File No. 58A/2170, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration Board Pages 737-747, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration Board Volume 6, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration Board Volume 4, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration Board Volume 3, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Arbitration Board Volume 2, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Arbitration Board Volume 1, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - U.S. National Mediation Board Arbitration Award Nos. 150-200, 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service -- Washington 25, D.C., 1958 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Misc., 1954-1957 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Letters Report, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - E.B. 110 - Travel Voucher's Correspondence, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Emergency Board 110 -- Reports, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Emergency Board 106 -- Miscellaneous, 1900-1952 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Emergency Board 106 -- Reports, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Vouchers - Travel + Personal Service, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Emergency Board 106 - Travel Vouchers Correspondence, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- NYC Transit Study; Puerto Rico Industry Papers (Box 11)
  - Minimum Wage Board - Puerto Rico, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Minimum Wage Board - P.R., 1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Senator Mitchell's Committee, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Mediation and Arbitration -- N.Y. state, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Various Data Rel: Transit Study, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Transit Material, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New York City Transit Authority, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - N.Y.C. Transit Authoriity, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - N.Y.C. Transit Authority -against- Theodore Loos, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - N.Y.C. Transit Industry Rough Material, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- NYC Transit Study; Puerto Rico Industry Papers (Box 12)
  - N.Y.C. City Transit Study - July 1957 to date (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - N.Y.C. Transit Study -- Jan. -Mar. 1997 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Joint Legislative Committee on Housing and Multiple Dwellings -- Cornell Meeting August 12-13, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Senate Committee on the Affairs of the City of New York (Senator MacNeil Mitchell), 1957 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - New York City, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Senates Committee on the Affairs of the City of New York, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate Seminar -- Transit Labor Relations, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Such Leave + Nicholnill, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Material, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Transit Annual Reports, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Waldman Bill, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Summaries - Transit Lab Rel. Bill + Transit Lab Rel. Situations, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous - TWUA, 1951-1957 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Field - Notes, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Labor Relations Problems (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Labor Relations Problem - 20 Pages, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Some Basic Issues, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Senate and Assembly Acts --, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - New York Journal American Transit Articles, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - New York Post, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Clippings -- New York City Transit "New York Times", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - New York News Transit, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - New York Mirror Transit Articles, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - New York Times - 1958 Transit Clippings (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Transit Strike News Items (Day Strike Ended), 1957 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Clippings -- New York City Transit "New York Herald Tribune", 1957 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - New York World - Telegram, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Papers Transit Strike Articles, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - City of N.Y. - Labor, 1954-1958 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Certificate of Copyright Registration - Library of Congress - "The American Story of Industrial Labor Relations by N.Y.S. Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions, of United States, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    incased
- Certificates, Awards (Box 13)
- Other Awards/Certificates (Box 14)